Modern Music Archives
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Modern Music Archives 1909-1983 (bulk 1924-1983)
ML31.M57
League of Composers (U.S.)
around 810 items 8 containers 5.75 linear feet Microfilm (93/20012 [MUS]--scrapbooks only)
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
The League of Composers was founded in New York in 1923 to promote American composers and introduce audiences to the best in new music through high quality performances. Its quarterly journal, Modern Music, was published from 1924 to 1946, and edited by Minna Lederman Daniel. It is one of the most distinguished collections of criticism and scholarship concerning early twentieth-century musical arts. The archives contains materials documenting the cessation of the journal, correspondence, financial and budget documents, fundraising materials, clippings, committee meeting minutes, photographs and artwork, stage and costume designs, contemporary concert and festival programs, scrapbooks containing promotional materials, publications of the League, and writings by Lederman Daniel.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Antheil, George, 1900-1959--Correspondence.; Antheil, George, 1900-1959--Portraits.; Berg, Alban, 1885-1935--Correspondence.; Berg, Alban, 1885-1935.; Brecht, Bertolt, 1898-1956.; Breton, André, 1896-1966.; Caruso, Enrico, 1873-1921.; Chanler, Theodore, 1902-1961--Correspondence.; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990--Correspondence.; Copland, Aaron, 1900-1990.; Cowell, Henry, 1897-1965--Correspondence.; Cowell, Henry, 1897-1965.; Cowell, Sidney Robertson, 1903-1995--Correspondence.; Cowell, Sidney Robertson, 1903-1995.; Denby, Edwin, 1903-1983.; Ewen, David, 1907-1985--Correspondence.; Gruenberg, Louis, 1884-1964--Portraits.; Heinsich, Richard.; Hindemith, Paul, 1895-1963--Portraits.; Jacobi, Frederick, 1891-1952--Correspondence.; Kirstein, Lincoln, 1907-1996--Correspondence.; Kirstein, Lincoln, 1907-1996.; Lederman, Minna--Photographs.; Lederman, Minna.; Lederman, Minna. Life and death of a small magazine (Modern music, 1924-1946).; Milhaud, Darius, 1892-1974--Portraits.; Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973.; Piston, Walter, 1894-1976--Correspondence.; Piston, Walter, 1894-1976.; Rosenfeld, Paul, 1890-1946--Correspondence.; Rosenfeld, Paul, 1890-1946.; Saminsky, Lazare, 1882-1959--Correspondence.; Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951--Correspondence.; Schoenberg, Arnold, 1874-1951--Portraits.; Shapero, Harold, 1920-; Shapero, Harold, 1920- --Correspondence.; Smirnoff, Boris, 1893?-1976.; Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989--Correspondence.; Thomson, Virgil, 1896-1989.
Organizations
League of Composers (U.S.); League of Composers (U.S.)
Subjects
Avant-garde (Music); Composers--Portraits.; Costume design--United States.; Music--20th century--History and criticism.; Musicology--United States.; Theaters--Stage-setting and scenery--Pictorial works.
Titles
League of Composers' review.; League of Composers' review.; Modern music (New York, N.Y.); Modern music (New York, N.Y.)
Form/Genre
Clippings (Information artifacts); Correspondence.; Financial records.; Photographic prints.; Portraits.; Programs (Documents); Promotional materials.; Scrapbooks.
Administrative Information
Provenance
The Modern Music Archives was given by Minna Lederman Daniel to the Library of Congress Music Division on September 30, 1975. Amendments to the instrument of gift were finalized on July 11, 1980. An edited typescript manuscript of Minna Lederman Daniel's book The Life and Death of a Small Magazine (Modern Music, 1924-1946) was added to the collection on March 23, 1984.
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Related Material
The Library of Congress Music Division holds the
Minna Lederman Daniel Collection
which contains correspondence, financial and legal papers, writings, clippings, and photographs belonging to Daniel, who was a founding member of the League of Composers and editor of Modern Music.
Access and Restrictions
The Modern Music Archives is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Music Division prior to visiting in order to determine whether the desired materials will be available at that time.
As of September 30, 2000, no written permission shall be required for single-copy reproductions of unpublished materials. Other restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Microfilm
The scrapbooks have been preserved on microfilm because of their fragile nature (Microfilm 93/20012 [MUS])
Agency Sketch
Date Event
1923 League of Composers founded in New York League of Composers seceded from Edgard Varèse's International Composers' Guild
1923 Fall Idea for League of Composers journal was conceived
1924 Feb. First issue of League of Composers' Review published with "intent to rouse the public out of a somnolent tolerance to a live appreciation of the new in music"
1925 Nov. Title changed to Modern Music
1931 Nov. Modern Music published A Guide to Wozzeck by Willi Reich
1944 July Modern Music and League of Composers moved into New York City Center offices Magazine staff comprised of: Minna Lederman, editor; Frani Muser, managing editor; Joel Lifflander, technical director; Donald Fuller, joined later as assistant editor
1944 Sept. Claire Reis withdrew as fundraising chairperson for Modern Music
1945 Modern Music received grants for 1946 operation costs from Ditson Fund, Wyman Fund, Guggenheim Foundation and Rockefeller Foundation
1946 Magazine board formed (independent of League of Composers) Circulation passed 3000 mark
1947, Jan. 11-13 Modern Music ceased publication G. Schirmer offered to take over publication of Modern Music Schirmer agreed to finance publication of index to Modern Music's twenty-three volumes (never completed)
1952 Willi Reich's A Guide to Wozzeck reprinted
circa 1953-1954 League of Composers merged with International Society for Contemporary Music
1965 Complete set of Modern Music reprinted by AMS Press
1975 Modern Music Archives deposited at Library of Congress
1976 Modern Music, Published by the League of Composers, 1924-1946: An Analytic Index, published by AMS Press; compiled by Wayne D. Shirley of the Library of Congress; edited by William and Carolyn Lichtenwanger
1984 The Life and Death of a Small Magazine (Modern Music, 1924-1946) written by Minna Lederman; published by Institute for Studies in American Music
Scope and Content Note
Modern Music, the quarterly journal of the League of Composers, was published in New York from 1924 to 1946 and edited by Minna Lederman Daniel. Initially the journal was known as The League of Composers' Review. In 1925, the name was changed to Modern Music, although the journal was still published under the auspices of the League. To this day, Modern Music is considered to be one of the most distinguished collections of criticism and scholarship concerning early twentieth-century musical arts. This publication is credited with nurturing an entire generation of composer-critics and for laying the stylistic groundwork for future generations. The roster of contributors includes composers, critics, scholars and artists, many of whom were in the prime of their careers. Exhibited among the twenty-three volumes of this short-lived yet critically-acclaimed journal are the talents of such noteworthy figures as Alban Berg, Aaron Copland, Walter Piston, Virgil Thomson, Paul Rosenfeld, Edwin Denby, André Breton, Lincoln Kirstein and Pablo Picasso, among others.
The original arrangement and series and subseries titles of this collection, which were designated by Minna Lederman Daniel prior to the collection's transfer, have been retained. The contents of the archives consists of materials documenting the cessation of the magazine. The Closing Activities series includes correspondence, financial and budget documents, fundraising materials, clippings, committee meeting minutes, and other materials that document the demise of Modern Music. In addition, it contains an essay by Minna Lederman Daniel entitled "Modern Music Archives: Footnotes to its History," which serves as an introduction to the archives. The Lederman Manuscripts series contains Lederman Daniel's annotated typewritten manuscript of The Life and Death of a Small Magazine (Modern Music, 1924-1946), which was published in 1983 by the Institute for Studies in American Music. The Correspondence series contains letters between Modern Music and its readers and contributors, and eight typescripts of articles submitted to Modern Music by Bertolt Brecht, André Breton, Henry and Sidney Cowell, Lincoln Kirstein, Harold Shapero, and others. The Iconography series includes photographs and artwork, both originals and reproductions, of composers, authors, and stage and costume designs. Noteworthy original works of art include self-portraits by Darius Milhaud and Arnold Schoenberg, sketches of George Antheil by Boris Smirnoff, a pencil drawing of Louis Gruenberg by Enrico Caruso, and a lithograph portrait of Paul Hindemith by Richard Heinsich. The Auxiliary Pamphlets series contains items of historical significance such as contemporary concert and festival programs, and other related lists and publications. The Supplemental Material series contains the final issue of Modern Music, the first issue of The League of Composers' Review, an index, and the monograph A Guide to Wozzeck by Willi Reich. And finally, the Scrapbooks series contains two scrapbooks containing promotional materials dating from 1924 to 1946 and press clippings from 1925 to 1947. The scrapbooks have been microfilmed. Throughout the collection are brief essays and explanations accompanying each series by Minna Lederman Daniel.
The following items described in Minna Lederman Daniel's itemized inventories were not located with the collection as of March 1993:
- File of correspondence to and from Hans Heinsheimer
- Group photo of "American composers at Copland's home"
- Photo of Stefan Wolpe
Peggy Monastra, March 1993
Organization of the Modern Music Archives
The Modern Music Archives is organized in eight series:
Closing Activities, 1945-1952, circa 1973
Lederman Manuscripts, circa 1983
Correspondence, 1925-1973
Iconography, 1909-1974
Scrapbooks, 1924-1947
Auxiliary Pamphlets, 1925-1938
Supplemental Material, 1924-1946
Oversize Iconography, 1928, 1934
http://lccn.loc.gov/2006571033
Container List
- Closing Activities, 1945-1952, circa 1973 (Box 1)
  Materials relating to the cessation of Modern Music.
  - Modern Music, 1924-1946: Footnotes to its History, by Minna Lederman, circa 1973, Typewritten manuscript; 22 p.; This document serves as an introduction (with footnotes) to the collection. (Box-folder 1/1)
  - "The Crisis," written by Minna Lederman, undated, Provides general information. (Box-folder 1/2)
  - Closing activities: decision to discontinue, by Minna Lederman, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Closing activities: auditor's report and supplement, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Closing activities: financing report--small magazine budgets, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Closing activities: last press release, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Closing activities: three New York press clippings (New York Sun, New York Times and the New York Tribune), 1946-1947 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Closing activities: closing announcement to donors, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Closing activities: return of money, 1946-1947, Correspondents: Bernstein, Leonard Carpenter, John Alden Harvard University, Music Department: G. Wallace Woodworth Ives, Mrs. Charles E. (photocopies) Jacobi, Frederick Latouche, John and Theodora Moore, Douglas Piston, Walter Raksin, David Rockefeller brothers; Arthur Packard and Arthur Jones, lawyers (Box-folder 1/3)
  - Preliminary letters: correspondence between Minna Lederman and Claire Reis, July-Sept., 1944 (Box-folder 1/4)
  - Fundraising: appeals, 1945-1946, Correspondents: American Council for Learned Societies: Donald Goodchild Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague Eastman School of Music: Howard Hanson Field Foundation / Yale University Press: E.M. Church (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Fundraising: grants pledged and received, 1945-1946, Correspondents: Bernstein, Leonard and Helen Coates, secretary Carpenter, John Alden Columbia University: Douglas Moore Harvard University: Walter Piston, G. Wallace Woodworth Ives, Mrs. Charles E. (photocopies) Jacobi, Frederick Latouche, John and Theodora Raksin, David (Box-folder 1/5)
  - Budget proposal, brochure on Modern Music--a plea for funding, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 1/6)
  - Grant correspondence from Modern Music to Rockefeller Foundation, Guggenheim Foundation, and Aaron Copland, 1945-1947, Carbons of letters; Contains original replies and related general information. (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Minutes of Modern Music committee meetings, 1946 (Box-folder 1/8)
  - Proposed acquisition by G. Schirmer, Inc., 1947 (Box-folder 1/9)
  - G. Schirmer publication of Wozzeck guide, general information by Minna Lederman, 1952 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - G. Schirmer publication of Wozzeck guide, correspondence, 1952 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - G. Schirmer publication of Wozzeck guide, reprint of guide, 1952 (Box-folder 1/10)
  - Letters of regret, 1947, Correspondents: Bernstein, Leonard Burk, John N. Carpenter, John Alden Chávez, Carlos Einstein, Alfred Frankenstein, Alfred Ginastera, Alberto Harrison, Lou Jacobi, Frederick Moore, Douglas Morton, Lawrence Shepherd, Arthur Smallens, Alexander Thompson, Randall Weinzweig, John Woodworth, G. Wallace Yates, Peter (Box-folder 1/11-15)
- Lederman Manuscripts, circa 1983 (Box 1)
  An edited typewritten manuscript of The Life and Death of a Small Magazine (Modern Music, 1924-1946), by Minna Lederman. Contains editorial markings and corrections; 136 p. The manuscript is divided into chapters.
  - Manuscript preface: reject pages, 15 p. (Box-folder 1/16)
  - Chapter one: "In the Beginning" (Box-folder 1/17)
  - Chapter two: "The Horizon Widens" (Box-folder 1/18)
  - Chapter three: "Trials, Tribulations and Triumphs" (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Chapter four: "War--Before, During and After" (Box-folder 1/20)
  - Chapter five: "Crisis and Closing" and "Envoi" (Box-folder 1/21)
- Correspondence, 1925-1973 (Box 2)
  Includes originals of letters sent to Modern Music, carbon copies of replies, photocopies of letters found in other Library of Congress Music Division collections (collected and copied by Minna Lederman and her assistants), and typescripts of articles submitted to Modern Music.
  Arranged alphabetically by name.
  - Antheil, George, 1925-1946 (Box-folder 2/1)
  - Berg, Alban, 1930-1935 (Box-folder 2/2)
  - Berman, Eugene, 1946 (Box-folder 2/3)
  - Blitzstein, Eva G., 1936 (Box-folder 2/4)
  - Bowles, Paul, 1943 (Box-folder 2/5)
  - Brecht, Bertolt, 1935-1936 (Box-folder 2/6)
  - Breton, André, 1944 (Box-folder 2/7)
  - Brunswick, Mark, 1937 (Box-folder 2/8)
  - Chanler, Theodore, 1946-1961 (Box-folder 2/9)
  - Columbia University. Office of Radio Research see Office of Radio Research
  - Coolidge, Elizabeth Sprague, 1938 (Box-folder 2/10)
  - Copland, Aaron, 1935-1946 (Box-folder 2/11)
  - Cowell, Henry, 1937-1940 (Box-folder 2/12)
  - Cowell, Sidney Robertson, 1943-1973 (Box-folder 2/13)
  - Denby, Edwin, 1943 (Box-folder 2/14)
  - Diamond, David, 1939-1940 (Box-folder 2/15)
  - Einstein, Alfred, 1928 (Box-folder 2/16)
  - Ewen, David, 1930-1935 (Box-folder 2/17)
  - Fine, Irving, 1944-1945 (Box-folder 2/18)
  - Gatti, Guido, 1945 (Box-folder 2/19)
  - Gilman, Lawrence, 1939 (Box-folder 2/20)
  - Heinsheimer, Hans, 1939, Contents of this folder not located as of Feb. 1993. (Box-folder 2/21)
  - Ives, Harmony Twichell, 1945-1947 (Box-folder 2/22)
  - Jacobi, Frederick, 1937-1945 (Box-folder 2/23)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln, 1934-1937 and 1946-1948 (Box-folder 2/24)
  - Kubik, Gail, 1943-1944 (Box-folder 2/25)
  - Mason, Redfern, 1928, Filed with Frederick Jacobi. (Box-folder 2/23)
  - McPhee, Colin, 1943 (Box-folder 2/26)
  - Office of Radio Research, 1943, Letter from Paul Lazarsfeld to Dr. John G. Peatman. (Box-folder 2/27)
  - Partisan Review, 1942-1943 (Box-folder 2/28)
  - Piston, Walter, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 2/29)
  - Rosenfeld, Paul, 1946 (Box-folder 2/30)
  - Saminsky, Lazare, 1925-1940 (Box-folder 2/31)
  - Schoenberg, Arnold, 1937 (Box-folder 2/32)
  - Shapero, Harold, 1945-1946 (Box-folder 2/33)
  - Still, William Grant, 1941 (Box-folder 2/34)
  - Stravinsky, Igor, 1944, Includes Minna Lederman's description and related commentary. (Box-folder 2/35)
  - Stuckenschmidt, H. H., 1930 (Box-folder 2/36)
  - Thompson, Randall, 1940 (Box-folder 2/37)
  - Thomson, Virgil, 1933-1946 (Box-folder 2/38)
  - Villa-Lobos, Heitor, 1940 (Box-folder 2/39)
- Iconography, 1909-1974 (Box 3-4, 8)
  - Composers
    Dates given refer to original portraits, not reproductions.
    - General introductory notes by Minna Lederman (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Antheil, George. Original pencil sketch of Antheil by Boris Smirnoff, undated, Signed. (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Antheil, George. Reproduction of sketch of Antheil by Smirnoff, Reproduced in Modern Music in May 1931. (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Argentine composers:, Castro, José Maria Castro, Juan José Castro, Washington Ficher, Jacobo Gianneo, Luis Morillo, Robert Garcéa (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Australian composers. Reproduction of drawings by B. Bowker, 1909, Agneo, Roy Hill, Alfred Hutchins, Frank (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Bartók, Bela. Reproduction of sketch of Bartók by J. Kmetty, 1925 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Bartók, Bela. Reproduction of sketch of Bartók, undated (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Berg, Alban. Reproduction of sketch of Berg by B.F. Dolbin, 1935, Includes a photocopy of photo of Berg with Franz Rederer from 1934. (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Berlin, Irving. Reproduction of sketch of Berlin by Stan[?], 1924 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Blitzstein, Marc. Reproduction of sketch of Blitzstein by Julian Levy, 1946 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Bloch, Ernest. Reproduction of sketch of Bloch by Ralph Stackpole, 1927 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Boulanger, Nadia. Reproduction of drawing of Boulanger by Clarence Brodeur (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Büchner, Georg. Reproduction of sketch of Büchner by HST, undated (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Buffano, Remo. Reproduction of sketch of Buffano by Frueh, 1926 (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Canadian composers. Reproduction of drawings by L. Orr, 1941, Applebaum, Louis Ridoud, Geoffrey Weinzweig, John (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Carpenter, John Alden. Reproduction of painting of Carpenter by Glyn Philpot, 1931 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Castro, Washington. Reproduction of line drawing of Castro, initialed "DW," undated (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Caturla, Alejandro Garcia. Reproduction of sketch of Caturla by Garcia Mora, 1940 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Chávez, Carlos. Reproductions of drawings of Chávez by Covarrubias, Rivera and Frueh, undated (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Chávez, Carlos. Reproduction of drawing of Chávez by Tamayo, 1969 (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Cocteau, Jean. Photocopy of photo of Cocteau by B. Abbott, undated (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Copland, Aaron. Reproductions of portraits of Copland by Dolbin, Frueh and O'Brien, undated (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Cowell, Henry. Reproduction of drawing of Cowell by C. Trowbridge, undated (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Delaunois, Raymonde. Reproduction of portrait, 1924 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Diaghilev, Serge. Reproduction of sketch of Diaghilev by Larioun [?], 1924 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Falla, Manuel de. Reproductions of drawings of Falla by Picasso, 1920 (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Gershwin, George. Reproductions of drawings of Gershwin by Frueh, 1924 and 1935 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Graham, Martha. Photocopy of photo of Graham from Le Sacre du Printemps, 1930 (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Group photo of American composers at Copland's home, Photograph missing as of February 1993.
    - Groupe des Six (Milhaud, Auric, Honegger, Tailleferre, Poulenc, and Durey) with Jean Cocteau, Photograph from published source (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Gruenberg, Louis. Original pencil drawing of Gruenberg by Enrico Caruso, 1920, Matted and signed. (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Harris, Roy. Reproductions of drawings of Harris by Walter Pach and A.M. Lahmer, circa 1933 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Hill, Edward Burlingame. Reproduction of portrait of Burlingame by Kathryn Nason, 1938 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Hindemith, Paul. Matted color lithograph of Hindemith by Richard Heinsich, 1934 see Oversize Iconography series
    - Hindemith, Paul. Reproduction of Heinsich lithograph (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Honegger, Arthur. Reproduction of portrait of Honegger by Camille Roche, 1925-1926 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Ives, Charles. Reproduction of photograph of Ives, undated (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Kern, Jerome. Reproduction of sketch of Kern by B. Dolbin, 1942 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Krenek, Ernst. Reproduction of painting of Krenek by F.A. Harta, 1930 (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Markevitch, Igor. Reproduction of painting of Markevitch by Pavel Tchelitchev, 1933 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Matisse, Henri. Reproduction of drawing "Head of a Dancer," 1939, Located in Composer file in accordance with Minna Lederman's arrangement. (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Milhaud, Darius. Original ink self-portrait, New York, 1940, Signed and matted. (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Milhaud, Darius. Reproduction of a portrait of Milhaud by Sotomayor, 1945 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Mills, Charles. Reproduction of painting of Mills by Franz Rederer, circa 1934 (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Piston, Walter. Reproduction of portrait of Piston by Kathryn Nason, undated (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Poulenc, Francis, Postcard (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Prokofiev, Sergei. Original pen and ink drawing by Natalia Gontcharova, 1928 see Oversize Iconography series
    - Prokofiev, Sergei. Small reproduction of Gontcharova drawing (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Revueltas, Silvestre. Ink drawing of Revueltas by F. Gamboa, 1940 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Roerich, Nicholas. Reproduction of photograph of Roerich, 1913 (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Satie, Erik. Reproduction of drawing of Satie by Pablo Picasso, circa 1920 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Schoenberg, Arnold. Reproductions of works of Schoenberg by Frueh, Sotomayor, and Kokoshka (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Schoenberg, Arnold. Reproduction of self-portrait, 1910 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Schoenberg, Arnold. Original ink-wash self-portrait, 1944 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Schuman, William see his entry under "Authors and Subjects"
    - Sessions, Roger. Reproduction of drawing of Sessions by Anny Schröder, 1933 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Shostakovich, Dmitri. Reproductions of portraits of Shostakovich by Shoemaker, Schmidt, and N. Akimov (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Stravinsky, Igor. Reproductions of a photo of Stravinsky, circa 1914; Picasso sketches, 1920; drawing by Sotomayor, 1945; and Sacre du Printemps drawing by Cocteau, 1913 (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Thomson, Virgil. Reproduction of sketch of Thomson by B. Dolbin, 1942 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Whithorne, Emerson. Reproduction of portrait of Whithorne by Robert W. Chandler, 1927 (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Wolpe, Stefan. Magazine reproduction of photograph of Wolpe, undated (Box-folder 3/11)
  - Stage and Costume Designs
    Photographs, drawings, printer's proofs, and reproductions of stage and costume designs. Most of these items were reproduced in the pages of Modern Music. Minna Lederman's original order has been mostly preserved in the arrangement of these items.
    - General information by Minna Lederman (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Antheil, George. Transatlantic, 1930, One reproduction (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Auric, Georges. La Concurrence, 1932-1933, One reproduction (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Bartók, Béla. The Miraculous Mandarin, 1941, One photograph (Box-folder 3/14)